window.__examLoadCallback({
  "title": "Computer_Network - Application_Layer_Protocols — Slot 1 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Application_Layer_Protocols — Slot 1",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>A user starts browsing a webpage hosted at a remote server. The browser opens a\nsingle TCP connection to fetch the entire webpage from the server. The webpage\nconsists of a top-level index page with multiple embedded image objects. Assume\nthat all caches (e.g., DNS cache, browser cache) are all initially empty. The\nfollowing packets leave the user's computer in some order.<br><br>\n(i) HTTP GET request for the index page<br>\n(ii) DNS request to resolve the web server's name to its IP address<br>\n(iii) HTTP GET request for an image object<br>\n(iv) TCP SYN to open a connection to the web server<br><br>\nWhich one of the following is the CORRECT chronological order (earliest in time\nto latest) of the packets leaving the computer ? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2024 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>(iv), (ii), (iii), (i)</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>(ii), (iv), (iii), (i)</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>(ii), (iv), (i), (iii)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>(iv), (ii), (i), (iii)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>(ii), (iv), (i), (iii)</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/422836/gate-cse-2024-set-1-question-6#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Suppose in a web browser, you click on the www.gate-2023.in URL. The browser\ncache is empty. The IP address for this URL is not cached in your local host, so\na DNS lookup is triggered (by the local DNS server deployed on your local host)\nover the 3-tier DNS hierarchy in an iterative mode. No resource records are cached\nanywhere across all DNS servers.<br>\nLet RTT denote the round trip time between your local host and DNS servers\nin the DNS hierarchy. The round trip time between the local host and the web\nserver hosting www.gate-2023.in is also equal to RTT. The HTML file associated\nwith the URL is small enough to have negligible transmission time and negligible\nrendering time by your web browser, which references 10 equally small objects on\nthe same web server.<br>\nWhich of the following statements is/are CORRECT about the minimum elapsed\ntime between clicking on the URL and your browser fully rendering it? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2023)</strong></p>",
          "type": "multiple",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>7 RTTs, in case of non-persistent HTTP with 5 parallel TCP connections.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>5 RTTs, in case of persistent HTTP with pipelining.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>9 RTTs, in case of non-persistent HTTP with 5 parallel TCP connections.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>6 RTTs, in case of persistent HTTP with pipelining.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": [
            "<b>C.</b> <p>9 RTTs, in case of non-persistent HTTP with 5 parallel TCP connections.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>6 RTTs, in case of persistent HTTP with pipelining.</p>"
          ],
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/399269/gate-cse-2023-question-42#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>Consider the resolution of the domain name \\(www.gate.org.in\\) by a DNS resolver. Assume that no resource records are cached anywhere across the DNS servers and that iterative query mechanism is used in the resolution. The number of DNS query-response pairs involved in completely resolving the domain name is . <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2022)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "4",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/371911/Gate-cse-2022-question-25#a_list_title\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>Remote Procedure Calls are used for <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>communication between two processes remotely different from each other on the same system</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>communication between two processes on the same system</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>communication between two processes on the separate systems</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>none of the above</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>none of the above</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "NOTE: Question is excluded from the evaluation due to ambiguity.<br> <a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/331457/isro2020-58\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Assume that you have made a request for a web page through your web browser to a web server. Initially the browser cache is empty. Further, the browser is configured to send HTTP requests in non-persistent mode. The web page contains text and five very small images.The minimum number of TCP connections required to display the web page completely in your browser is__________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2020)</strong></p>",
          "type": "numeric",
          "options": [],
          "correct_answer": "6",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/333206/gate2020-cs-25#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following protocol pairs can be used to send and retrieve e-mails (in that order)? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2019)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>IMAP POP3</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>SMTP, POP3</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>SMTP, MIME</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>IMAP, SMTP</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>SMTP, POP3</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/302832/gate2019-cs-16#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>What is WPA? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>wired protected access</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>wi-fi protected access</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>wired process access</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>wi-fi process access</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>wi-fi protected access</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128670/isro2017-38\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Which protocol suite designed by IETF to provide security for a packet at the Internet layer? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>IPSec</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>NetSec</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>PacketSec</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>SSL</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>IPSec</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128668/isro2017-36\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following protocol is used for transferring electronic mail messages from one machine to another? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2017)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>TELNET</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>FTP</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>SNMP</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>SMTP</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>SMTP</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/128659/isro2017-31\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>When a DNS server accepts and uses incorrect information from a host that has no authority giving that information, then it is called <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2016)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>DNS lookup</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>DNS hijacking</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>DNS spoofing</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>None of the mentioned</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>DNS spoofing</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/55536/isro2016-80\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Identify the correct sequence in which the following packets are transmitted on the network by a host when a browser requests a webpage from a remote server,assuming that the host has just been restarted. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>HTTP GET request, DNS query, TCP SYN</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>DNS query, HTTP GET request, TCP SYN</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>DNS query,TCP SYN, HTTP GET request</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>TCP SYN, DNS query, HTTP GET request</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>DNS query,TCP SYN, HTTP GET request</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39572/gate2016-2-25#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>Which of the following is/are example(s) of stateful application layer protocols?<br>\n(i) HTTP <br>\n(ii) FTP <br>\n(iii) TCP <br>\n(iv) POP3 <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>(i) and(ii)only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>(ii) and(iii)only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>(ii) and(iv)only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>(iv)only</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>(ii) and(iv)only</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39628/gate2016-1-25#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Which statement is false? <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>PING is a TCP/IP application that sends datagrams once every second in the hope of an echo response from the machine being PINGED</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>If the machine is connected and running a TCP/IP protocol stack, it should respond to the PING datagram with a datagram of its own</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>If PING encounters an error condition, an ICMP message is not returned</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>PING display the time of the return response in milliseconds or one of several error message</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>If PING encounters an error condition, an ICMP message is not returned</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/51980/isro2015-56\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>The DNS maps the IP address to <br><br><strong>(ISRO CSE 2015)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A binary address as strings</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>A n alphanumeric address</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>A hierarchy of domain names</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>A hexadecimal address</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>A hierarchy of domain names</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/46736/isro2015-44\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Which one of the following statements is NOT correct about HTTP cookies? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2015 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>A cookie is a piece of code that has the potential to compromise the security of an Internet user</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>A cookie gains entry to the user's work area through an HTTP header</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>A cookie has an expiry date and time</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Cookies can be used to track the browsing pattern of a user at a particular site</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>A cookie is a piece of code that has the potential to compromise the security of an Internet user</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/8063/gate2015-2-25#a_list\" targer=\"_blank\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
});
